<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Eric Jain&#39;s Blog</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://eric.jain.name/"/>
  <updated>2018-11-22T18:20:38.019Z</updated>
  <id>http://eric.jain.name/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Eric Jain</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tracking Blood Sugar</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2018/11/25/tracking-blood-sugar/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2018/11/25/tracking-blood-sugar/</id>
    <published>2018-11-25T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-11-22T18:20:38.019Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fasting glucose and A1C tests done over the past few years show me at low risk for diabetes. But these tests don’t necessarily capture how much blood sugar “spikes” after meals–something that may be <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.2005143">a better predictor of disease risk</a>. Blood sugar spikes can be minimized with a suitable diet, but what that diet should consist of <a href="http://thepersonalizeddiet.com/">differs from person to person</a>. Fortunately, measuring your blood sugar responses is now relatively affordable and hassle-free with the latest generation of Continuous Glucose Monitors.</p><h2 id="What-I-did"><a href="#What-I-did" class="headerlink" title="What I did"></a>What I did</h2><p>At my last physical exam, I asked for a prescription for a <a href="https://www.freestylelibre.us/">FreeStyle Libre</a>. The setup consists of a reader device (which may <a href="https://www.abbott.com/corpnewsroom/product-and-innovation/freestyle-librelink.html">no longer be necessary</a>), and disposable sensors that last two weeks each. The reader device can also process blood test strips, so I got some of those as well (and some lancets) so I could check the accuracy of the sensors.</p><p><img src="hardware.jpg" alt="FreeStyle Libre"></p><p>For four weeks I tried to follow a normal life, eating and doing the things I normally do, with a few small variations, and while keeping an eye open for problematic blood sugar responses (i.e. outside of the 70-140mg/dL range).</p><p>I scanned the sensor with the reader before breakfast, lunch and dinner every day, as well as just before going to bed and right after getting up (as the sensor starts overwriting data after just 8 hours). Also in between, sometimes, out of curiosity.</p><p>The official <a href="https://www.freestylelibre.us/support/overview.html">desktop</a> and <a href="https://www.libreview.com/">web</a> apps generate nice reports for physicians and can export your data as a spreadsheet, but transfering data from the reader with <a href="https://tidepool.org/">Tidepool</a> was less flaky, plus their mobile app let me describe meals better (i.e. not just mark meal times).</p><p>Tidepool does a good job visualizing the data, but I wanted to have each day ligned up, and include per-hour step counts from my Fitbit to get an idea of activity levels and sleep times. So I <a href="https://support.tidepool.org/article/37-export-your-account-data">exported my data from Tidepool</a> and created this chart with <a href="https://altair-viz.github.io/">Altair</a> in a Jupyter Notebook:</p><p><img src="timeline.png" alt="timeline chart"></p><p>To compare blood sugar responses for specific meals, I extracted and overlaid data into charts like this one, comparing the blood sugar responses for several breakfasts:</p><p><img src="breakfast.png" alt="breakfast chart"></p><p>For reference, I also kept a record of all my activities with the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/timeline">Google Maps Timeline</a>, including photos of <del>all</del> most of my meals.</p><h2 id="What-I-learned"><a href="#What-I-learned" class="headerlink" title="What I learned"></a>What I learned</h2><p>The sensors worked as advertised, and didn’t cause any pain or skin issues, or come off prematurely. The local swimming pool was closed for the duration of the experiment, but I do shower at least once a day. If I were spending more time in the water, or with skin exposed to the sun, or doing rougher activities, I’d consider covering the sensor with something like SIMPATCH tape.</p><p>The sensors appeared to be reasonably accurate: The extrapolated glucose levels shown when scanning the sensor were often way off, but the “historic” values that are logged with a lag every 15 minutes or so seemed plausible, and matched the few finger prick tests I did, at least when blood sugar levels were stable.</p><p>I had planned to do a few more finger prick tests, but getting enough blood to do a measurement for comparison turned out to be surprisingly difficult. Should have gotten a wider lancet (i.e. 23g instead of 30g), but pharmacies don’t seem to stock those…</p><ul><li>chocolate and pastries and ice cream YES</li><li>regular pasta NO</li><li>smoothie bowl &gt; smoothie</li><li>insufficient sleep NO</li><li>light activity like walking after meals YES</li><li>stress NO</li><li>overeating NO</li></ul><p>Blood sugar stays stable while hiking regardless of what I eat. But there is no immediate effect that improves glucose tolerance for snacks or dinner after hiking (though presumably regular exercise improves glucose tolerance).</p><p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> This was the least problematic meal. Oatmeal causes a stronger glycemic response than granola, or even French toast smothered in apple sauce or maple syrup. Granola with less cane sugar is better, and <a href="https://www.bobsredmill.com/old-country-style-muesli.html">muesli</a> with no aded sugar is best.</p><p>Adding whey protein to my breakfast does/doesn’t make a difference (TBD)?</p><p>Skipping my 7-minute exercise session before breakfast once doesn’t make a difference (though it’s possible it might make a long-term difference if I skipped it every day).</p><p>Replacing full-fat with low-fat yoghurt in my breakfast smoothie doesn’t make an obvious difference.</p><p><strong>Lunch:</strong> places to avoid?</p><p><strong>Mid-afternoon snacking:</strong> Chocolate, nuts, ice cream, apples are all unproblematic, as are cookies and cakes, in moderation. Not so good: Mochi.</p><p><strong>Dinner:</strong> More problematic than lunch.</p><p><strong>Post-workout snack:</strong> Milkshakes: Not a problem after an intense, half hour workout in the evening. But not so good if taken without exercising. No difference if taken immediately after exercising while still at the gym, or a bit later when back home.</p><ul><li><p>walking reduces blood sugar spikes. due to slower digestion, or due to <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5610683/">better processing</a>? Apple juice experiment.</p></li><li><p>lack of sleep makes the blood sugar response less effective (higher peak, longer tail)</p></li><li>also, eating outside of schedule!</li><li><p>dehydration</p></li><li><p>exercise vs walking vs standing vs sitting vs slouching</p></li><li><p>cortisol and melatonin down-regulate insulin production</p></li></ul><p>I will be presenting more detailed results at <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Quantified-Self-Seattle/">the next Seattle Quantified Self meetup</a>.</p><h2 id="What-next"><a href="#What-next" class="headerlink" title="What next"></a>What next</h2><p>I intend to do another round of blood sugar tracking in a year or so, or earlier, if my daily routine changes significantly.</p><p>Some questions I hope to answer in the future are:</p><ul><li>Do high/low blood sugar levels at night affect sleep quality?</li><li>Does fluid intake (incl herbal tea) affect blood sugar levels?</li><li>Does chewing gum (Xylitol) affect blood sugar levels?</li><li>How much do blood sugar levels drop during an overnight camping trip?</li><li>Does the meal duration (and sequencing of items) affect blood sugar levels?</li><li>How does fasting (skipping one or more meals) affect blood sugar levels?</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Fasting glucose and A1C tests done over the past few years show me at low risk for diabetes. But these tests don’t necessarily capture ho
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Quantified Self" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/quantified-self/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chocolate Popcorn</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2018/11/22/chocolate-popcorn/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2018/11/22/chocolate-popcorn/</id>
    <published>2018-11-22T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-11-22T19:03:29.466Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A somewhat healthy, but addictive snack.</p><p><img src="chocolate-popcorn.jpg" alt=""></p><ul><li>¼ cup <a href="https://www.bobsredmill.com/yellow-popcorn.html">popcorn</a></li><li>1 cup <a href="https://www.ghirardelli.com/dark-chocolate-60-cacao-baking-chips-%2810-oz%29-61274">chocolate chips</a></li><li>¼ cup maple syrup</li><li>¼ cup honey</li><li>1 tsp vanilla</li></ul><p>Pop the pocorn in the microwave.</p><p>Melt the chocolate chips with the maple syrup, honey and vanilla, and pour over the popcorn on a baking sheet.</p><p>Bake for 30 minutes at 300F, stirring every 10 minutes.</p><p>Let cool for another 30 minutes, again stirring every 10 minutes.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;A somewhat healthy, but addictive snack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;chocolate-popcorn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;¼ cup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bobsredm
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Recipe" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/recipe/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Fake Trails</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2018/10/25/fake-trails/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2018/10/25/fake-trails/</id>
    <published>2018-10-25T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-10-26T04:03:50.628Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One in five pictures I take while hiking are pictures of the trails themselves. Previously, I experimented with <a href="https://github.com/ejain/n-of-1-ml/blob/master/transfer_learning.ipynb">using machine learning to automatically tag those pictures</a>. After reading about how machine learning can be used not just for image classification, but also for <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1511.06434">generating images</a>, I was curious to see what would happen if I tried this approach on my pictures.</p><p>Here are a few randomly selected pictures of trails, out of the more than 5,000 pictures of trails I have taken over the past 10 years:</p><p><img src="real_samples.png" alt="actual trails"></p><p>After a bit of number crunching with a <em>Deep Convolutional Generative Adversarial Network</em> (where part of the network is trained to fake images, while the other part is simultaneously being trained to detect fake images), here are a few randomly generated trail pictures: </p><p><img src="fake_samples_epoch_275.png" alt="fake trails"></p><p>There is some blurriness and some distortions, but overall the results are pretty convincing! There are forest trails, trails through alpine meadows, rocky trails, and even a few snow-covered trails. But none of these trails exist in the real world.</p><h2 id="Notes"><a href="#Notes" class="headerlink" title="Notes"></a>Notes</h2><ul><li><p>I ended up using <a href="https://pytorch.org/">PyTorch</a>, which happened to have <a href="https://github.com/pytorch/examples/tree/master/dcgan">suitable sample code</a>. <a href="https://keras.io/">Keras</a> (my go-to framework) turned out to be a bit too high-level to handle this kind of problem efficiently, and <a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/">Tensorflow</a>, being more low-level, would have required more code.</p></li><li><p>Unfortunately, scaling up beyond 64x64 thumbnails to 128x128 or larger turns out to not be a simple matter of throwing more computing resources at the problem.</p></li><li><p>The network was trained for 275 epochs (iterations through the entire data set). This animation shows how the generated images improved over time: </p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EtQbLnecW0g" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></li><li><p>The training was done on a fast machine with a GPU (obtained from <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sagemaker/">Amazon SageMaker</a> for a total cost of about $2); running the same code on my laptop would have taken days, rather than just under an hour.</p></li><li><p>Found <a href="https://github.com/soumith/ganhacks">this list of tips</a> that might further improve the results.</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;One in five pictures I take while hiking are pictures of the trails themselves. Previously, I experimented with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.c
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Programming" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/programming/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Panna Cotta</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2018/09/24/panna-cotta/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2018/09/24/panna-cotta/</id>
    <published>2018-09-24T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-25T04:14:08.535Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A fancy-looking desert that is quick and simple to prepare… Serves 4.</p><p><img src="panna-cotta.jpg" alt=""></p><ul><li>1 cup whole milk</li><li>1 cup heavy whipping cream</li><li>2 tbsp sugar </li><li>2 tsp agar agar powder</li><li>1 tsp vanilla</li></ul><p>Combine ingredients in a saucepan and bring to a simmer. Let cool for a few minutes before pouring into forms. Refrigerate.</p><p>For the raspberry coulis topping:</p><ul><li>1 cup frozen raspberries</li><li>¼ cup sugar</li></ul><p>Disolve the sugar in 1 tbsp of hot water. Combine with raspberries and blend briefly (long enough to crush the raspberries, but not long enough to pulverize the seeds). Strain through a narrow sieve. Layer on top of the panna cotta before serving.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;A fancy-looking desert that is quick and simple to prepare… Serves 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;panna-cotta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup whole 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Recipe" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/recipe/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Programmer Excuses</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/10/29/programmer-excuses/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/10/29/programmer-excuses/</id>
    <published>2017-10-29T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-10-29T21:33:20.981Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="comic.png" alt="compiling, testing, training"></p><p>(based on <a href="https://xkcd.com/303/">xkcd.com/303/</a>)</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;comic.png&quot; alt=&quot;compiling, testing, training&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/303/&quot;&gt;xkcd.com/303/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Humor" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/humor/"/>
    
      <category term="Programming" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/programming/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cascades Pika Watch</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/08/31/cascades-pika-watch/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/08/31/cascades-pika-watch/</id>
    <published>2017-08-31T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-09-01T01:09:01.494Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4XyTyp9VJA4WAJbNn493W1XV3SFMqzUVvEymWOWnaM9lxmtJOJ7-Jr6xDcKNMeUpyzV-xM7TRBUYsv0g8yfryLIzEOGzQAiB711meqDkH5ZXSpaxjn60W63SxG7R9_219YDNKlzTDA=w1022-h767-no" alt="Pika near Cascade Pass"></p><p>This summer we participated in a “citizen science” project that has us report any signs of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_pika">Pikas</a> we came across while hiking.</p><p>To get started, we attended a training session at <a href="https://www.pdza.org/">Point Defiance Zoo</a> earlier this year, to ensure we wouldn’t confuse pikas with squirrels or other small mammals, and to learn how to identify pikas from their calls or scat.</p><p>The observations were reported through <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nrel.citsci">an Android app</a>. Each report includes not just the place and time of the observation, but also the number of animals, whether we saw or only heard them etc. The app was a bit tedious (and buggy), wish they had chosen <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.inaturalist.android">iNaturalist</a> instead.</p><p>The observation data is publicly available at <a href="http://www.citsci.org/cwis438/Browse/Project/Project_Info.php?ProjectID=339">CitSci.org</a>. So far we contributed 5 observations, hoping to get a few more before winter!</p><p>There’s also a fun <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/CascadesPikaWatch/">Facebook group</a> where people share pictures.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4XyTyp9VJA4WAJbNn493W1XV3SFMqzUVvEymWOWnaM9lxmtJOJ7-Jr6xDcKNMeUpyzV-xM7TRBUYsv0g8yfryLIzEOGzQ
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First Aid Kit</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/03/17/first-aid-kit/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/03/17/first-aid-kit/</id>
    <published>2017-03-17T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-17T06:22:58.132Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are the contents of the first aid kit I <a href="/2017/03/05/vehicle-equipment/">keep in the car</a>, and take along on hikes.</p><p><img src="contents.jpg" alt=""></p><ol><li><a href="http://kk.org/cooltools/fenix-l1dce-fla/">Flashlight</a></li><li>Oral Rehydration Salts</li><li><a href="https://grabberwarmers.com/warmer-products/">Hand Warmer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.adventuremedicalkits.com/quikclot-advanced-clotting-sponge-50g-2.html">QuikClot Sponge</a></li><li>Paracord</li><li>Signal Mirror</li><li><a href="https://www.katadyn.com/us/us/403-8014996-micropur-mp1-20-usa-only">Water Purification Tablets</a></li><li>Insect Bite Wipes</li><li>Antibiotic Ointment</li><li>Medications (Aspirin, Diamode, Ibuprofen, Diphenhydramine)</li><li>Sun Screen</li><li>Duct Tape</li><li>Gauze</li><li>Medical Tape</li><li>Nivea Cream</li><li>Fire Lighter</li><li>Towel</li><li>Gauze Pads</li><li>Blister Pads</li><li>Band-Aids</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Here are the contents of the first aid kit I &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/03/05/vehicle-equipment/&quot;&gt;keep in the car&lt;/a&gt;, and take along on hikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Gear" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/gear/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Vehicle Equipment</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/03/05/vehicle-equipment/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/03/05/vehicle-equipment/</id>
    <published>2017-03-05T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-19T21:19:21.843Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is all the gear I keep in the car. Other than a couple of short trips around town during the week, most of the driving is to and from trailheads.</p><p><img src="images/gear.jpg" alt=""></p><ol><li><a href="http://autosock.us/">Tire Socks</a>. Never used, but they count as <a href="http://www.wsp.wa.gov/traveler/traction.htm">approved traction devices</a> here when cars are required to carry chains.</li><li>Emergency Triangle</li><li><a href="http://snowclaw.com/">Snow Shovel</a></li><li><a href="/2017/03/17/first-aid-kit/">First Aid Kit</a>. This also goes along on hikes.</li><li><a href="http://www.techmatte.com/CBL-ATC5B">USB Cable, 5ft</a></li><li><a href="https://www.monoprice.com/product?c_id=116&amp;cp_id=10826&amp;cs_id=1082603&amp;p_id=13810&amp;seq=1&amp;format=2">USB Car Charger</a></li><li><a href="https://www.kenu.com/products/airframe">Phone Mount</a></li><li>Water, 1L</li><li>Recreation Passes (<a href="https://www.nps.gov/planyourvisit/passes.htm">Interagency Pass</a>, <a href="http://www.discoverpass.wa.gov/">Discover Pass</a>, <a href="http://parks.state.wa.us/303/Sno-Parks">Sno-Park Permit</a>)</li><li>Map</li><li>Disposable Sunglasses</li><li>Paper</li><li><a href="http://tekton.com/Air_Hoses/Tire_Gauges/Digital-Tire-Gauge-100-PSI">Tire Gauge</a></li><li><a href="http://5hourenergy.com/">Energy Drink</a></li><li>Hand Sanitizer</li><li>Microfiber Towel</li><li>Rain Poncho</li><li>Safety Vest</li><li>Blanket</li><li>Wire Saw</li><li><a href="http://www.suaoki.com/rcp-c43l.html">Air Compressor</a></li><li><a href="https://www.anker.com/products/A1501011">Jump Starter</a></li><li><a href="https://www.fixaflat.com/us/product-details.php?id=14">Fix-a-Flat</a></li><li><a href="http://www.orionsignals.com/product-groups/handheld-flares/product/20.html">Road Flares</a> (not shown)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YI3IGA6/ref=cm_sw_su_dp">ShadeSox</a> (not shown). Used as a bug net when sleeping in the car with the rear windows open.</li><li><a href="https://www.containerstore.com/s/grey-utility-trays/d?productId=10035847">Utility Trays</a></li><li><a href="https://www.automatic.com/">Automatic</a> OBD Adapter (not shown). Records <a href="/2015/01/01/outdoor-trips/">tracklogs</a>, gas mileage, cost per trip, and other useful data.</li></ol><div class="gallery">      <div class="row">    <div class="col-sm-4">    <div class="thumbnail">      <a href="images/tire.jpg"><img src="thumbnails/tire.jpg"/></a>        <div class="caption">          Items 1-3 go under here...        </div>    </div>  </div>      <div class="col-sm-4">    <div class="thumbnail">      <a href="images/trunk.jpg"><img src="thumbnails/trunk.jpg"/></a>        <div class="caption">          ...and 17-25 fit inside the trays.        </div>    </div>  </div>      </div>  </div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This is all the gear I keep in the car. Other than a couple of short trips around town during the week, most of the driving is to and fro
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Gear" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/gear/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/02/24/hexo/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/02/24/hexo/</id>
    <published>2017-02-24T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-12T06:44:28.740Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog started out on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yahoo!_GeoCities">GeoCities</a> sometime during the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot-com_bubble">dot-com bubble</a>. Somewhere along the way I moved it to a proper hosting provider (first <a href="guest-hosting.ch">guest-hosting.ch</a>, then <a href="https://www.rackspace.com/en-us">Rackspace</a>), acquired a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.name">.name</a> domain, and set up a custom <a href="https://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a> installation.</p><p>This setup was flexible, but meant I had to stay on top of security updates for WordPress (until automatic updates were introduced), remember to update the packages installed on the server (Ubuntu) once in a while, and deal with occasional comment spam. Also, page load times weren’t great (even with various caching plugins), since the site was being served from a low-end virtual server, which nevertheless cost me about $10 a month.</p><p>This made going back to serving simple, static files an attractive option. <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a> was an obvious choice for hosting the site, since I already had several projects on GitHub. I’d also need a <em>static site generator</em> to create the web pages from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a> files I exported from WordPress:</p><ul><li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> would have been the default choice, since GitHub Pages has built-in support for Jekyll. But I wanted to be able to build the site on my own machine as well, and that turned out to be painful to set up, and very slow.</li><li><a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> appeared to have most of the same features, and was much faster.</li><li><a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a> seemed fast enough, and easier for me to customize than Hugo.</li></ul><p>I ended up creating a custom theme for Hexo based on <a href="https://github.com/klugjo/hexo-theme-clean-blog">this theme</a>.</p><p><img src="blog.png" alt="Screenshot"></p><p>Since switching to serving static pages, I no longer need to worry about security updates. Pages are served fast (<a href="https://uptimerobot.com/">UptimeRobot</a> reports response times of well under 100ms). I do miss having a bit more control (like being able to change the cache headers), but so far so good…</p><p>You can see the source code for this site <a href="https://github.com/ejain/blog/">here</a> (the source itself is in the <code>master</code> branch, and the generated pages in the <code>gh-pages</code> branch).</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This blog started out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yahoo!_GeoCities&quot;&gt;GeoCities&lt;/a&gt; sometime during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.w
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Protein Shakes</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/01/06/protein-shakes/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/01/06/protein-shakes/</id>
    <published>2017-01-06T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-17T05:43:15.983Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s the recipe for my favorite post-exercise recovery drink:</p><p><img src="ingredients.jpg" alt=""></p><ol><li>1 cup milk (or random <a href="http://www.pacificfoods.com/food/non-dairy-beverages.aspx">non-dairy beverage</a>)</li><li>3 scoops <a href="https://www.raworganicwhey.com/">whey protein</a></li><li>1 tsp <a href="https://healthworks.com/products/healthworks-raw-certified-organic-cacao-powder-1-lb">cacao powder</a></li><li>1 tsp <a href="http://cbsnuts.com/wp/product/16oz-jar-cbs-peanut-butter-usa-grown/">peanut butter</a></li><li>1 <a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-gives-5000-bananas-day-seattle/">banana</a></li></ol><p><a href="https://www.nutribulletpro.com/">Blending</a> this for half a minute results in a smooth, tasty shake. Goes well with dates or figs.</p><p><img src="shake.jpg" alt=""></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Here’s the recipe for my favorite post-exercise recovery drink:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ingredients.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup milk (or ran
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Recipe" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/recipe/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Smoothies</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2017/01/06/smoothies/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2017/01/06/smoothies/</id>
    <published>2017-01-06T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-05T23:29:53.899Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Upgraded my breakfast from cereal with yoghurt to “smoothie bowls” last year. After a lot of experimenting, here’s what I’ve settled on (for now):</p><p><img src="ingredients.jpg" alt=""></p><ol><li>1 cup yoghurt</li><li>1 tsp spirulina</li><li>1 tsp chia seeds</li><li>2 tsp golden flaxseed meal</li><li>1 cup frozen fruit (mango, pineapple, strawberry, caranberry, blueberry, banana)</li><li>1 leaf collard green and lacinato kale</li></ol><p>I <a href="https://www.nutribulletpro.com/">blend this</a> for just under a minute, sprinkle some granola on top, and this is the result:</p><p><img src="bowl.jpg" alt=""></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Upgraded my breakfast from cereal with yoghurt to “smoothie bowls” last year. After a lot of experimenting, here’s what I’ve settled on (
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Recipe" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/recipe/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Subaru Crosstrek</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2016/09/17/subaru-crosstrek/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2016/09/17/subaru-crosstrek/</id>
    <published>2016-09-17T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-06T02:40:36.238Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With my 2008 Honda Civic approaching 100K miles, I decided it was time to replace it. The Civic had been very reliable, and put up with a lot of abuse from driving on bumpy dirt roads without any problems–apart from one broken motor mount. But I didn’t want to push my luck. Also, the upcoming winter is forecast to have proper snow again…</p><p>Requirements:</p><ul><li>Good ground clearance and suspension, so I don’t have to crawl around every pothole, and be afraid of scraping the bottom of the car.</li><li>Similar width and length as the old car, so I can park the car around town without causing too much damage.</li><li>Adaptive cruise control, so I can use cruise control even when the road isn’t empty (and feel like the new car is more sophisticated than the old car).</li><li>Silver color, so dirt and scratches aren’t quite as visble.</li><li>Decent gas mileage (at least 30mpg).</li><li>Cost &lt;$30K.</li></ul><p>Cars I considered:</p><ul><li>Honda HRV</li><li>Mazda CX-5</li><li>Subaru Crosstrek</li></ul><p>The HRV would have been an obvious choice, given my good experience with the Civic and the <a href="http://www.hondaofseattle.com/">Honda of Seattle</a> service department. Unfortunately, the HRV doesn’t have an option for adaptive cruise control (need to get the larger CRV for that), and the ground clearance isn’t great. The CX-5 and the Crosstrek have similar ground clearance, features, safety ratings etc. The CX-5 has an option for a more powerful engine, but feels more like an SUV than a compact car, so I decided to check out the Crosstrek first.</p><p>I test-drove a Crosstrek two weeks ago at <a href="http://www.chaplinssubaru.com/">Chaplin Subaru</a>, and loved it, but no one had the configuration I was looking for. <a href="http://www.royrobinson.com/">Roy Robinson Subaru</a> was one of 3 dealers in the region to receive a matching Crosstrek today (and one of the easiest to deal with), so that’s who got my business!</p><p><img src="crosstrek.jpg" alt="Crosstrek 2.0i Premium"></p><p>Things I learned:</p><ul><li>Some dealers are still having a hard time with the internet. Had to restate my original request up to three times before getting an answer from some of them.</li><li>If you are buying a popular model, finding a dealer who has a vehicle available can be tricky.</li><li>Even so, every dealer (with the exception of Carter Subaru in Seattle) was willing the match prices, and sell at $1K “below invoice”, which happened to correspond to the price I got from <a href="https://www.truecar.com/">TrueCar</a>.</li><li>Local sales taxes differ slightly from dealer to dealer; this can add up to a few hundred $.</li><li>Dealers load up cars with optional features you might not need; doing a factory order could have saved me almost $1K.</li><li>…however, negotiating a <a href="https://www.kbb.com/used-cars/">good trade-in value</a> for the old car would have been difficult with a factory order (which takes at least 6 weeks to deliver).</li><li>Doing a trade-in has significant tax advantages.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;With my 2008 Honda Civic approaching 100K miles, I decided it was time to replace it. The Civic had been very reliable, and put up with a
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Gear" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/gear/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Flights in 2015</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2016/01/01/flights/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2016/01/01/flights/</id>
    <published>2016-01-01T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-27T01:30:40.937Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Collected tracks for every flight I took last year from <a href="https://flightaware.com/">FlightAware</a>, and used <a href="https://gist.github.com/ejain/ea143f446bb568ec20d6">this script</a> to merge the tracks into a single file that could be imported into <a href="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/">Google Fusion Tables</a>. This is the result:</p><p><a href="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?q=select+col2+from+1TTaW_pw0b4ZgeHeO4H7xkqY6MNLRqD8Z2cZUeXdO&amp;viz=MAP&amp;h=false&amp;lat=32.63587469625332&amp;lng=-93.51910237499999&amp;t=1&amp;z=4&amp;l=col2&amp;y=2&amp;tmplt=2&amp;hml=KML"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/2/1607/23343129434_34a5ac61cc_z.jpg" alt="Flight Map"></a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Collected tracks for every flight I took last year from &lt;a href=&quot;https://flightaware.com/&quot;&gt;FlightAware&lt;/a&gt;, and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://gis
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Quantified Self" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/quantified-self/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Outdoor Trips in 2014</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2015/01/01/outdoor-trips/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2015/01/01/outdoor-trips/</id>
    <published>2015-01-01T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-25T06:21:35.186Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking back at all the outdoor trips we did last year, <a href="https://zenobase.com/#/buckets/u07qih0a27/?q=timestamp:2014">the stats</a> look almost identical to the previous year’s. Couple more overnight trips (10), thanks to the great weather. All in all, we hiked and paddled about 470 mi with 110,000 ft elevation gain on 59 trips.</p><p><a href="https://www.google.com/fusiontables/embedviz?q=select+col5+from+1qqRIewHtmcROWgAtyAWkFd50jF7IyIG_pdAcj-SX&amp;viz=MAP&amp;h=false&amp;lat=47.273650754137826&amp;lng=-122.05635518652345&amp;t=4&amp;z=8&amp;l=col5&amp;y=2&amp;tmplt=2&amp;hml=KML"><img src="http://farm8.static.flickr.com/7521/15996138219_aa9bcdef84_o.png" alt="Tracklogs"></a></p><p>See <a href="/2010/12/12/one-years-tracklogs/">this previous post</a> for an explanation how this map was created.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Looking back at all the outdoor trips we did last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zenobase.com/#/buckets/u07qih0a27/?q=timestamp:2014&quot;&gt;the stats&lt;/
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Quantified Self" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/quantified-self/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tableau &amp; Quantified Self</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2014/05/24/tableau-quantified-self/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2014/05/24/tableau-quantified-self/</id>
    <published>2014-05-24T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-25T06:20:19.808Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tableau has a <a href="http://www.tableausoftware.com/public/contest/QS">contest</a> going on for visualizing Quantified Self data. I happen to have a fair amount of such of data from all kinds of sources on <a href="https://zenobase.com/">zenobase.com</a>, so I decided to give it a shot.</p><p>I was curious about Tableau’s geo features, and how well Tableau would handle slightly larger data sets. So I chose some outdoor/fitness activity data (which includes coordinates), and some hour-resolution energy expenditure data (~10K records).</p><p>Getting the data into Tableau was straightforward, as Zenobase exports data in <acronym>CSV</acronym> format. Tableau didn’t detect any data types (timestamps, coordinates, or even numbers), but that was easy to fix after the import had completed. Working with the larger data set was not a problem, either, even if the experience wasn’t exactly snappy.</p><p>You can find the result embedded below. The “dashboard” is interactive, so you can select one or more days of the week (and/or hours of the day), and the map will update to show activities that started at the corresponding time. Or you can select an activity type, or a region on the map.* Note the different patterns on week days and week ends.</p><p><p><script type='text/javascript' src='http://public.tableausoftware.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js'></script></p></p><div class='tableauPlaceholder' style='width: 654px; height: 879px;'><noscript><a href='#'><img alt='Dashboard ' src='http:&#47;&#47;public.tableausoftware.com&#47;static&#47;images&#47;Ac&#47;ActivitiesCaloriesBurned&#47;Dashboard&#47;1_rss.png' style='border: none' /></a></noscript><object class='tableauViz' width='654' height='879' style='display:none;'><param name='host_url' value='http%3A%2F%2Fpublic.tableausoftware.com%2F' /><param name='site_root' value='' /><param name='name' value='ActivitiesCaloriesBurned&#47;Dashboard' /><param name='tabs' value='no' /><param name='toolbar' value='yes' /><param name='static_image' value='http:&#47;&#47;public.tableausoftware.com&#47;static&#47;images&#47;Ac&#47;ActivitiesCaloriesBurned&#47;Dashboard&#47;1.png' /><param name='animate_transition' value='yes' /><param name='display_static_image' value='yes' /><param name='display_spinner' value='yes' /><param name='display_overlay' value='yes' /><param name='display_count' value='yes' /><param name='filter' value='amp;:showVizHome=no' /></object></div><br><div style='width:654px;height:22px;padding:0px 10px 0px 0px;color:black;font:normal 8pt verdana,helvetica,arial,sans-serif;'></div><p>* If the submission deadline wasn’t this Sunday evening, and I wasn’t on my way out to “collect more data”, perhaps I could try to show the energy expenditure on the map, and let selections on the map update the energy expenditure data below as well…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Tableau has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tableausoftware.com/public/contest/QS&quot;&gt;contest&lt;/a&gt; going on for visualizing Quantified Self data. I hap
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Quantified Self" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/quantified-self/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>EuroSeattle Startup Weekend</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2014/01/29/euroseattle-startup-weekend/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2014/01/29/euroseattle-startup-weekend/</id>
    <published>2014-01-29T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T08:18:03.015Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend I attended my first <a href="http://euroseattle.startupweekend.org/">Startup Weekend</a>. The event was very well organized; I had a great time and got to know a lot of good people.</p><p>Didn’t get enough votes for the idea I pitched (a dating site that matches people using data from services like Fitbit), so I ended up joining another team to build <a href="http://www.myloop.co/">an app that generates running routes that pass near popular sights</a>.</p><p><img src="myloop_app.png" title="Generated route starting at Louisa's Cafe" width="180" height="300"/></p><p>Our team consisted of 6 “non-technicals” and 3 developers (including myself). There was little friction, and I was impressed how well tasks like market research were performed. Somewhat less impressive was the amount of time spent discussing logos and background colors. Also, does the “Minimum Viable Product” really need a built-in music player? :-)</p><p>Despite Startup Weekend’s slogan (“No Talk, All Action”), there isn’t much incentive to put a lot of development effort into anything but building smoke and mirrors: Even though we had what appeared to be the only (somewhat) usable product, we didn’t even make it into the top 4…</p><p>Every Startup Weekend is probably unique, but it would be more worthwhile for developers if there was some technical mentorship, and judges also took execution into consideration, not just business plans.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Last weekend I attended my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://euroseattle.startupweekend.org/&quot;&gt;Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;. The event was very well organized;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Programming" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/programming/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>API Prayer</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2013/10/11/api-prayer/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2013/10/11/api-prayer/</id>
    <published>2013-10-11T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T08:18:03.002Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Our Father in heaven,</p><p>hallowed be your OAuth tokens.</p><p>Your data come,</p><p>your quota will be increased,</p><p>in the sandbox, as well as in production.</p><p>Give us this day out daily stats,</p><p>and forgive us our outdated docs,</p><p>as we have also forgiven those whose timestamps lack time zone offsets.</p><p>And lead us not into premature standardization,</p><p>but deliver us from expired SSL certificates.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hallowed be your OAuth tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your data come,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your quota will be increased,&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Humor" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/humor/"/>
    
      <category term="Programming" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/programming/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lenovo Thinkpad T431s</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2013/07/05/lenovo-thinkpad-t431s/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2013/07/05/lenovo-thinkpad-t431s/</id>
    <published>2013-07-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T08:18:02.991Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Got a Thinkpad T431s to replace my 3-year old T410s. Here are some random observations, after using the new laptop for a few weeks.</p><p><img src="T431s.jpg" alt="T431s"></p><p>The T431s feels much lighter than the T410s. The screen is a bit smaller (still 14”, but more elongated), and the T431s lacks a DVD reader/writer, but I won’t miss that to much. On the other hand I find the fingerprint reader (not faster than typing, but less awkward when typing in front of other people) and the memory card reader (can transfer pictures from a camera fast and without having to search for the right cable) quite useful.</p><p>I like the backlit keyboard better than the light on the previous models. I’m less happy about the random placement of the Home/End/PgUp/PgDn keys, which I use a lot. I wouldn’t mind if I could at least map Fn+Up to PgUp, Fn+Left to Home etc, but this does not appear to be possible (tried with KeyTweak). I also use the F keys a lot; these are now by default used to control volume, brightness etc. There is a FnLk, but that has to be reset after waking up from standby.</p><p>One of the nice things with Thinkpads is the ability to create custom configurations. I no longer care much about CPUs (Intel Core i7-3687U, 4M Cache, 2.00 GHz), but chose twice the RAM (8G RAM) that I had in the T410s. The disk is a 180GB SSD (would have chosen 250GB, if that had been an option). Had to spend some time removing unwanted trial applications (anti-virus, office), and the large recovery partition and local drivers (after creating a recovery USB drive).</p><p>The T431s appears to be much more quiet than the T410s. The T410s had some weird screeching sounds (a known problem with some chipset used in that machine), and was prone to overheating, especially when using the “discrete” ATI graphics card. The “switchable graphics” setup is no longer an option, but the integrated Intel HD Graphics 4000 is now powerful enough for me.</p><p>The large, smooth trackpad on the T431s is much more pleasant to use than the rough trackpad on the T410s with its poorly defined borders. The trackpad does rattle and feel a bit cheap when depressing it, but I prefer to click by tapping lightly anyway. Should just glue it in place :-)</p><p>The DisplayPort is gone, replaced with a (much more common) Mini-DisplayPort. There’s still a VGA port, too. All ports are now on the sides. The T431s still works with the Mini Dock Series 3, using a small (included) piece of plastic to help guide the laptop into position.</p><p>The power adapter has been shrunk a bit, which is nice. The power plug was changed as well: It’s no longer round, but looks like (and could be confused with) a USB plug.</p><p>The battery life isn’t very impressive, but I seem to get at least 3 hours when using wifi and a reasonable screen brightness. Also, the contrast and brightness of the screen are rather poor. This would be an issue, if I didn’t have the laptop connected to an external monitor most of the time.</p><p>Like with previous Thinkpads, the build quality looks good. There is a new hinge design; I’m curious to see how fast the hinges wear out. The hinges on the T410s were a weak spot, wearing out after only a year or so (compared to the hinges on the T42p, which didn’t show any signs of wear even after several years).</p><p>All in all, the T431s has been a worthwhile upgrade for me. I’ll keep this post updated…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Got a Thinkpad T431s to replace my 3-year old T410s. Here are some random observations, after using the new laptop for a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Review" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/review/"/>
    
      <category term="Programming" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/programming/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>California Roadtrip</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2012/03/24/california-roadtrip/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2012/03/24/california-roadtrip/</id>
    <published>2012-03-24T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-25T06:52:50.659Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a map with tracks, waypoints and links to photo albums from a one-week trip from Los Angeles to San Francisco and back (March 15–22).</p><iframe src="map.html" height="600" width="550"></iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Here’s a map with tracks, waypoints and links to photo albums from a one-week trip from Los Angeles to San Francisco and back (March 15–2
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>OSGi and Eclipse RCP Talk</title>
    <link href="http://eric.jain.name/2011/11/17/osgi-and-eclipse-rcp-talk/"/>
    <id>http://eric.jain.name/2011/11/17/osgi-and-eclipse-rcp-talk/</id>
    <published>2011-11-17T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T08:18:02.976Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I gave a talk at the <a href="http://www.seajug.org/">Seattle Java User Group</a> this week, where I talk about two technologies I use <a href="http://www.sciscogenetics.com/">at work</a>: The <a href="http://www.osgi.org/About/Technology">OSGi</a> module system, and the <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/index.php/Rich_Client_Platform">Eclipse Rich Client Platform</a>. Giving this talk was a good experience, and the audience was great. You can watch the talk below, or flip through <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/ejain/osgi-and-eclipse-rcp">the slides</a>.</p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/32248135" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seajug.org/&quot;&gt;Seattle Java User Group&lt;/a&gt; this week, where I talk about two technologies I use &lt;a
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Life Science" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/life-science/"/>
    
      <category term="Programming" scheme="http://eric.jain.name/tags/programming/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
